## **Summary**

Experienced Software Engineer with over 4 years of experience, showcasing strong proficiency in PHP and Python. Possesses additional programming skills in JavaScript (NodeJS and ReactJS) and extensive knowledge of databases including MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, and SQLite. Skilled in creating and integrating RESTful APIS, DevOps processes and AWS Cloud Computing.

Seeking a challenging position to utilize automation and improve software development, expanding my knowledge and providing opportunities for greater responsibilities and advancement

# **FEMI DAUDA**

## **Contact**

Phone: +2347064203959 E-Mail: daudafd@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/femidauda-971534b5/

Github: https://github.com/daudafd

## **Technical Skills**

- CI/CD: Git versioning, DevOps, CloudFormation
- Front-End: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, ReactJS
- Back-End: PHP, Python (Django), NodeJS
- Databases: SQL, NoSQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite.

#### **Certifications**

- Agile Project Management
- Full Stack Web Development with React Specialization
- JavaScript Certification
- Getting started with DevOps
- DevOps on AWS Specialization
- AWS Cloud Technical Essentials
- AWS Fundamentals: Addressing Security Risk
- Personal Effectives & Assertiveness Skills

## Other skills

- Problem solving
- Effective communication
- · Creative thinking
- Innovative
- Service-focused

## **Experience**

## Software Engineer - Kosibound

2023 - presently

- Led migration projects from legacy systems to modern architectures, improving system efficiency by 30%.
- Collaborated cross-functionally to deliver projects on time and within budget, recognized for exceptional teamwork and problem-solving skills.
- Developed robust APIs using PHP (Laravel) and optimized database structures in MySQL and PostgreSQL for enhanced scalability and performance.
- Utilized Django framework to build secure and scalable web applications, integrating with complex database architectures.
- Implemented RESTful APIs in Node.js for efficient data retrieval, enhancing system performance and scalability.
- Utilized React to create dynamic user interfaces, improving the user experience and reducing bounce rates.
- Integrated continuous integration and continuous delivery (CI/CD) pipelines to automate the deployment process.

#### Software Engineer -Ondo State Internal Revenue Service

2019 - 2023

- Cooperate with designers to create clean interfaces and simple, intuitive interactions and experiences.
- Developed tasks for front-end public and internal websites as well as challenging back-end server code with a team of developers.
- Work with other developers to manage large, complex design projects for corporate clients.
- Carried out quality assurance tests to discover errors and optimize usability.
- Support the roll-out of new applications (or referral to third parties, if appropriate).

#### **Education**

**Higher National Diploma : Computer Science -**

2013 - 2015

Rufus Giwa Polytechnic, Owo.

Project: Development of e-parking system for democracy park Akure

National Diploma: Computer Science -

2010 - 2012

Crown Polytechnic, Ado-Ekiti.

**Project:** Development of Bio-metric data capture system